Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（火神(かがみ)）ん… んあ
It's finally time.
（火神）いよいよだな
ウインターカップ
セミファイナル…
The Winter Cup semifinals.
Our rematch against Kaijo. Against Kise.
海常(かいじょう)… 黄瀬との再戦
Let's do this.
やってやる！
（アレックス）あ〜ん
Alex, what—
（火神）おい！ ど… だっ…
Why are you sleeping in my bed?!
なんでオレのベッドで
寝てんだよ！
It's super cold.
チョーさみーから
布団取らないでくれよ
Don't take all the covers.
Then put some clothes on!
なら服を着ろ！
テメエ 師匠が教えた必殺技で
服たたきつけるだと!?
How dare you throw clothes at your
master using a move I taught you?!
はあ… ったく
Sheesh...
アレックス
ゆうべは大丈夫だったか？
Alex, were you okay last night?
Yeah, of course.
（アレックス）ああ もちろん
（火神）タツヤは？
What about Tatsuya?
It was just a scratch.
（アレックス）かすり傷だ
He went back to his hotel
immediately afterwards.
あのあと すぐホテルに帰ったよ
I see.
そうか
I can imagine why you showed up then.
あのとき
オマエが何しに来たのか—
だいたい見当はついてる
Don't worry.
心配すんな
I'm sure Tatsuya felt the same way.
それは きっとタツヤも同じだ
Yeah.
（アレックス）それより
支度はできてるのか？
Anyway, are you ready?
Yeah, of course.
ああ もちろん…
Huh?
あれ？
I'll Take It
Your shoes fell apart?!
（リコ）バッシュ壊れた!?
バカタレ！
You idiot! Why do you only have one pair?!
ていうか なんで
一足しか持ってないのよ!?
What's wrong with you guys?
ったく 何なの アンタらは？
こんなところまで
タイミング合わせないでよね！
You don't have to be in sync like this, too.
You guys?
アンタら？
Hello.
（黒子(くろこ)）どうも
つうか なんでオマエも
バッシュ壊してんだよ
Why are your shoes falling apart?
I could ask you the same thing.
（黒子）それは
こっちのセリフです
We can't find my size anywhere.
オレのサイズだけ
どこ行ってもねえ…
火神君 足デカいですからね
ムダに
Kagami-kun, your feet are pointlessly large.
“ムダに”って何だよ！
What do you mean, pointlessly?
（火神）お！
こんなところにもあった
Hey, there's a place here.
I'm going to go ask.
ちょっと聞いてくるわ
（葉山(はやま)）わー！
どいて！ どいてっ！
Move, move!
（葉山）えいっ！
（葉山）ああ ごめんな
ちょっと急いでて
Oh, sorry! I'm in a hurry...
Oh, crap!
うわあ ヤバイ！
ホントごめん
I'm really sorry!
（火神）あっ あのジャージ…
That jacket...
Did they have your size?
ありましたか？
No.
なかった…
Very well.
（黒子）分かりました
（火神）ん？
Huh?
I'll ask. She usually comes
through in times like these.
ちょっと聞いてみましょう
こういうとき
すごく頼りになります
Their basketball shoes fell apart?
（日向(ひゅうが)）バッシュが壊れた!?
２人同時にって…
なんだそりゃ
Both of them at the same
time? Are you serious?
Will they make it in time?
（木吉(きよし)）間に合うか？
まあ 時間は大丈夫でしょう
They'll probably be okay on time.
ウチの試合は夕方からだし
Our match is in the evening.
わっ！ あー ちょっちょっ…
たっ…
Whoops.
（実渕(みぶち)）おっと
（リコ）あっ すいま…
Sorry...
Oh, are you okay?
（実渕）あらあら 大丈夫？
気をつけないとダメよ
You should be careful.
Th-Thanks...
ど… どうも…
Coach!
（日向）カントク！
ちょっと〜
女の子は ちゃんと守ってあげてね
Hey, you've got to protect your girl.
あの人…
That guy...
Let's see.
（降旗(ふりはた)）え〜と
Tape, cold spray, and...
テーピングと
コールドスプレーと…
Is that everything?
これで全部かな？
（福田(ふくだ)）あっ あとドリンクの粉
We need powdered drink mix, too.
（河原(かわはら)）ん？ ああ！
（降旗）どうした？
What is it?
（根武谷(ねぶや)）ん… うーん
（根武谷）うえー 特盛！
（店員）はい
Give me more.
Y-Yes, sir.
（降旗）うっわ 何だ あれ？
What's with that guy?
（河原）火神より食ってね？
He's eating more than Kagami.
（福田）しかもムキムキ…
プロレスラーかよ
And he's ripped. Is he a pro wrestler?
Tetsu-kun!
（さつき）テツくーん！
Sorry for calling so suddenly.
すみません 急に電話して…
ううん 全然！
ていうか チョーうれしー！
It's totally fine.
In fact, I'm so happy.
I appreciate you helping us look for shoes,
バッシュ探してくれんのは
いいけどよ…
つうか なんでオマエがいんだよ！
but what are you doing here?!
（青峰(あおみね)）聞きてえのは
こっちだっつうんだよ
I could ask you the same thing.
Dai-chan has lots of basketball shoes,
and he said you could have some.
大(だい)ちゃん バッシュいっぱい
持ってるから くれるって
What? I didn't say that!
（青峰）ンだよそれ 言ってねえよ
ふざけんな さつき！
Don't be ridiculous, Satsuki!
You guys wear the same size, right?
足のサイズも同じでしょ？
29.5 centimeters.
29,5センチ
How do you know that?!
（火神）なんで知ってんの？
Here.
（さつき）はい！
（青峰）うおおい！
Hey! You can't just take my shoes!
（青峰）勝手に持ってくんなよ
オレのバッシュ！
These are the same ones I wear...
（火神）これは
オレが使ってるのと同じ…
He happened to have a pair.
ちょうど一足あったの
They're a different color.
カラーリングは違うけど—
But you've always worn the same
type of shoes, right, Kagamin?
かがみんて同じモデルを
使い続けるタイプなんでしょ？
（火神）情報網マジパねえ！
つうか かがみん!?
Her information network must be insane!
And did she say Kagamin?!
But...
（火神）しかし…
この色もいいな
This isn't a bad color.
ふう しょうがねえ
Fine. If you can beat me
one-on-one, you can have them.
ワンオンワンで
オレに勝ったらやるよ
Why do I have to do that?!
（火神）なんで そうなんだよ！
この後 試合あんだけど！
I have a game after this!
（青峰）３本勝負だ すぐ終わる
We'll play a best of three.
It'll be quick.
I told you...
（火神）だから！
Just do it.
（青峰）いいからやれ
While we're at it, I'll give you a lecture.
ついでだ
ちょっとレクチャーしてやる
Aomine-kun punched Haizaki-kun?
（黒子）青峰君が灰崎君を殴った？
But you could say he had
to do it to help Ki-chan...
あ… でもね—
きーちゃん助けるために
しょうがなくっていうか
う… それってバレたら
マズいんじゃないですか？
Wouldn't it be bad if someone found out?
Yeah.
But I don't think Shogo-kun
will do anything else.
けど…
祥吾(しょうご)君は
もう何もしない気がする
I'm not sure how to put it,
うまく言えないけど…
大ちゃんに止められて—
but I think he's kind of
relieved Dai-chan stopped him.
どこか ほっとしてるところも
あると思うんだ
ひねくれてるけど
それでも—
He's twisted, but they both wore
Teiko uniforms at one point.
帝光のユニフォームを
一緒に着てたヤツだし
Satsuki,
（青峰）さつき
終わったから帰んぞ
I'm finished. Let's go.
（さつき）あ… 早くない？
Isn't it a little soon?
すぐ終わるっつったろ
I said it wouldn't take long.
How did it go?
どうでしたか？
I crushed him.
圧勝
Hey, wait!
待てよ おい！
もっかい！ もっかいだ！
One more! One more time!
I want the shoes, but more than
anything I hate ending on a loss!
バッシュも欲しいし—
何より負けたままは
納得いかねえ
Let's go one more time!
もう一度勝負だ！
（青峰）試合があんだろ？
何言ってんだよ
Don't you have a game?
What are you talking about?
Here.
（青峰）ほら
（火神）え？
They're yours.
（青峰）やる
（火神）どういうことだよ
What's going on?
Either way, I don't need them anymore.
（青峰）どっちにしろ
もういんねえし
I... I can't take these when I lost!
なっ… 負けっ放しで
もらえっかよ！ 返す！
Take them back!
Just wear them, you idiot!
いいから履けよ バカ！
You're good the way you are.
オマエは それでいいんだよ
And you're playing Kise, right?
それに黄瀬とやんだろうが
If you play like trash because you're
wearing uncomfortable shoes, I'll kill you.
合わねえバッシュで
ナメた試合したらブッ殺すぞ
勝負は中断ってことにしといてやる
We'll postpone our match.
（火神）じゃあ…
Thanks, then. I'll take them.
ワリーな もらっとくわ
We're just postponing our game!
中断だからな あくまで！
Just go!
行けよ 早く！
Seirin High
Locker Room
（火神）スンマセン
遅くなりました
Sorry I'm late.
You're late.
（日向）遅(おせ)えよ！
Did you get shoes?
（リコ）ちゃんとバッシュ買えた？
（火神）うす
（黒子）はい
Yeah.
Yes.
The Rakuzan-Shutoku game is starting soon.
そろそろだな
洛山(らくざん) 対 秀徳の試合
Um, just how strong is Rakuzan?
あの… 洛山って
どれくらい強いんですか？
They're a super strong school
that's been participating
（日向）ウインターカップ開催
第１回から—
in the Winter Cup since its inception.
ずっと出場してる超強豪だ
They've won more tournaments
than any other school.
優勝回数は全校中最多
For the past five years they've
won all three major titles.
最近の戦勝は
５年間連続３大タイトル総ナメ
In a word, they're the
strongest high school team.
ひと言で言えば—
高校最強だ
（１年生たち）はっ…
And their lineup this year is
the strongest it's ever been.
そして…
その中でも今年は過去最強の
布陣と言われている
Akashi Seijuro of the Generation of Miracles.
“キセキの世代”
赤司征十郎… スか？
Yeah, but he's not the only one.
ああ
だが それだけじゃない
Do you remember the Uncrowned Kings?
“無冠の五将”って
覚えてるか？
Five prodigies overshadowed
by the Generation of Miracles.
“キセキの世代”の
陰に埋もれた５人の天才—
木吉と花宮(はなみや)…
There's Kiyoshi and Hanamiya.
And the remaining three
players are all on Rakuzan.
そして残り３人は
すべて洛山にいる
I am unfamiliar with loss.
（赤司）オレは敗北を知らない
What?
（緑間）何？
何だ それは？ 嫌味か？
Is that a snide remark?
ふっ… いや すまない
No, I'm sorry.
It was just a thought.
ただ 今 ふと思っただけだ
決して望んでいるわけじゃない
It's not something I desire.
知らないから
興味があるというだけだ
I'm simply interested in
it because it's unfamiliar.
それ以上の意味はない
I meant nothing more than that.
それを嫌味と言うのだよ
That's what you call a snide remark.
If that's the case, I will
introduce you to it eventually.
ならば
いずれオレが教えてやる
ふっ… そうだな
You're right.
If we ever face each other, I don't
think I'll be able to hold back.
もし オマエと
戦うことになれば—
さすがに手加減は できなそうだ
Though I have no intention of losing.
負ける気は毛頭ないがな
ふん
（赤司）ところで真太郎
By the way, Shintaro...
Shut up. I concede.
（緑間）うるさい！
投了なのだよ
（木村(きむら)）緑間 何だそれ？
Midorima, what is that?
My lucky item.
ラッキーアイテムです
おお 今日は小っちゃくていいや
Today's is nice and small.
What's your rank today?
（宮地(みやじ)）んで 今日は何位？
Second.
（緑間）２位ですが
What? You should at least take first.
何だそりゃ
１位取ってこいよ 埋めんぞ
I'll bury you.
But it's my fortune.
（緑間）いや 占いなんで
（高尾(たかお)の笑い声）
（中谷(なかたに)のため息）
It's time! Let's go!
（大坪(おおつぼ)）よーし時間だ！
行くぞ！
Yeah!
（秀徳選手たち）おう！
They're out!
（観客１）出た！
11年連続出場の古豪！
The veterans of 11 consecutive appearances!
The veteran kings, Shutoku High!
（観客２）歴戦の王者
秀徳高校！
They're here!
（観客３）そして 来た
（観客４）高校最強
The strongest high school team!
The emperors since the beginning
of time, Rakuzan High!
（観客３）開闢(かいびゃく)の帝王
洛山高校！
（根武谷）う〜ん 食い過ぎた
I ate too much.
That's gross.
きったないわね！
Why would you eat so much before a game?
ていうか試合前にドカ食いって
何なわけ？
I'm stronger when I eat meat.
オレは肉食ったほうが
力 出んだよ
Anyway, look! Look at them!
それより見て見て！
あいつら！ ヤベーって！
They're bad news!
Shut up.
うっさいわね！
強そー！ マジ？ ヤッベー！
They look seriously strong, dude. Crap!
Right, Akashi?
な？ 赤司
Yes, they are strong.
ああ 彼らは強いよ
What? Sei-chan, you're starting today?
（実渕）え？
征(せい)ちゃん 今日スタメン？
監督も同意済みだ
The coach already approved.
へえ… そりゃいいな
Really? That's good.
No one we've played against
so far stood a chance.
ここまでずっと歯ごたえねえ
相手ばっかだったからな
Maybe I should've eaten more.
もっと食っときゃよかった
I put the towels over there.
（洛山部員）タオル
そこ置いときました
Okay.
Let's go.
じゃあ 行こうか
Since they're so strong,
I thought they'd be more uptight.
なんか強いトコだし—
もっとギスギスしてんのかと
思ったけど
They're pretty normal, though.
なんつうか普通ですね
（宮地）何言ってんだ 焼くぞ
What are you talking about?
You're going to get burned.
There's nothing normal about them.
（宮地）むしろ異常だろ
（高尾）え？
No. 4 is their captain, Akashi.
４番ってことは
赤司がキャプテンだ
今年入ったばかりの１年
No matter how amazing a first year
is, that almost never happens.
どんなすごいヤツでもありえねえぞ
普通そんなん
What's even more incredible is
not a single player on the bench
しかも
もっとありえねえのは—
そのことについてベンチ含め—
チーム全体に不満が
まったく感じられねえことだ
or the rest of the team seems
to have a problem with it.
Neither do the Uncrowned Kings.
しかも“無冠の五将”もだぜ
They all have their quirks
and a lot of pride.
それぞれが
ひとクセもふたクセもあって—
プライドも高い
All of them accept him as their captain.
そいつらが全員
そろいもそろって受け入れている
As someone who knows them,
something seems really out of place.
知ってるヤツから見たら
違和感バリバリだ
At the very least,
少なくとも—
you can't call someone who
leads so naturally "normal."
あんな自然に
人を従える人間を—
“普通”とは言わねえよ
（紫原）あーもー めんどくさー
What a pain in the ass.
If you want to watch the game,
watch it yourself, Murochin.
てか見たいなら
１人で見に来りゃいいじゃん
室(むろ)ちんさー
Don't be that way, Atsushi.
（氷室(ひむろ)）まあ そう言うなよ 敦
Can I leave?
（紫原）やっぱ帰っていい…
（氷室）のりしおもあるぞ
I have seaweed and salt chips.
食う
I'll have some.
It's starting.
（氷室）ほら 始まるぞ
どっちが勝つと思う？
Who do you think will win?
Who knows?
さあ？
When it comes to shogi,
Akachin's never lost a game.
とりあえず将棋じゃ
赤ちん負けたことないけど
Shogi?
将棋？
They played a lot during breaks.
よく２人で休み時間とかに
やってたの
I can't imagine Akachin losing.
ま やっぱ赤ちんが負けるトコは
想像できないかな
I'm going to win, Akashi.
勝たせてもらうぞ 赤司
That's impossible, Shintaro.
それは無理だ 真太郎
Have you ever forced me to concede?
一度でも僕に投了させたことが
あったかい？
将棋とバスケは違うのだよ
Shogi and basketball are different.
They are the same.
同じさ
僕が今まで間違ったことを
言ったことは一度もない
I have never been wrong.
Because I always win, I am always right.
すべてに勝つ僕は
すべて正しい
The first semifinal game of the Winter Cup
（審判）これよりウインターカップ
準決勝 第１試合—
between Rakuzan High and
Shutoku High will now begin!
洛山高校 対 秀徳高校の
試合を始めます
（審判）礼！
（一同）よろしくお願いします！
Bow!
Let's have a good game!
Yeah!
（高尾）っしゃあ！
Just kidding.
なんてな
（葉山）げっ！
ヤッベー いきなり？
Crap! Already?
You're always right?
すべて正しいだと？
笑わせるな 赤司
Don't make me laugh, Akashi.
Don't talk like you know everything
when you've only ever won!
勝ったことしか
ないようなヤツが—
知ったような口をきくなよ！
Come, Akashi.
（緑間）来い 赤司
約束どおり教えてやる
As promised, I will teach you
about loss.
敗北を
Really?
へえ
（観客１）おお！
リングにかする気配すらねえ！
It didn't even touch the hoop!
（観客２）精密機械だ まるで！
He's like a high-precision machine!
He's got an aura around him.
（高尾）さっすがオーラあんね
ったく… ホントに同じ１年かよ
Sheesh. Is he really a first year?
Takao, you're on Akashi. Got it?
（中谷）赤司のマークは高尾
オマエだ いいな？
Sure thing. Can I say something, though?
（高尾）はい
ああ でも１ついいっスか？
Sorry if I can't handle it.
無理だったらスンマセン
いや 頑張れよ！
つうか やる気あんのか オイ!?
No, do your best!
Are you even trying?
I'll do my best!
やる気は そりゃ あるっスよ！
けど緑間が
ビビるようなヤツっスからね
But even Midorima's scared of him!
I'm not scared!
ビビってないのだよ！
Don't turn on us!
開き直んな！
（高尾）集中しろ！
Focus.
Focus, focus, focus.
集中… 集中… 集中！
速(はえ)え！ けど…
He's fast! But...
Nice pass!
（根武谷）ナイスパス！
Rakuzan
Shutoku
The first quarter's over!
（観客１）ここで
第１クオーター終了か！
Neither the kings nor emperors
are giving any ground!
（観客２）王者と帝王
どっちも譲らねえ！
Atsushi, was he really
the captain of your team?
敦…
彼は本当にオマエと同じチームの
キャプテンか？
ん？ そーだけど
Yeah.
What's going on?
（高尾）どうなってやがる
確かに上手(うめ)え
スキルもあるし 視野も広い
He's definitely good.
He's got the skills, and he
has a broad field of vision.
He's as good as you'd expect
a point guard to be.
ポイントガードとしての
完成度は さすがのひと言だ
けど手も足も出ないほどの
実力差じゃない
But he's not so good that I can't keep up.
Is this really the captain of the
Generation of Miracles, Akashi Seijuro?
これが“キセキの世代”
キャプテン 赤司征十郎？
The game's going well.
（白金(しろがね)）順調だな
No changes to our game plan.
ゲームプランに変更はない
I'll leave the detailed
game-making to you guys.
細かいゲームメイクは任せる
修正が必要なら 赤司に従え
If you need to fix anything,
listen to Akashi.
Yes, sir!
（一同）おす
Akashi's definitely not holding back.
（中谷）赤司は決して
手を抜いているわけではないよ
将棋をほうふつとさせるね
この運び方は
The course of this game
closely resembles shogi.
Right now we're still feeling each other out.
今はまだ序盤の探り合いと
いったところだ
They'll probably start making their move...
そして局面が動くとしたら
うん…
...soon.
そろそろかな
Anyway, we should try to make the first move.
というわけで
まずはこっちから仕掛けてみよう
The break is over!
（審判）インターバル終了
第２クオーター開始！
The second quarter will now begin!
Don't underestimate me, Akashi.
（緑間）ナメるなよ 赤司
第１クオーター丸々
様子見とは—
It was rather leisurely of you to so obviously
watch and wait during the first quarter.
随分のんびりしているな
Surely you don't think you can
win without using your "eye."
まさかオマエの“眼”を使わずに
勝とうなどと思っていないだろうな
I don't underestimate you, Shintaro.
ナメてなどいないよ 真太郎
If anything, I couldn't
be playing more carefully.
むしろ この上なく慎重に
進めているぐらいだ
切り札をそう簡単に
切るわけにはいかないさ
One must be careful how
they play their trump card.
ただし…
However,
at this rate the game may
end before I even play it.
切らずに終わってしまうかも
しれないな
このままでは
What did you say?
何だと？
They're
これは！
緑間にダブルチーム！
double teaming Midorima!
And Shin-chan doesn't know what to do?
（高尾）しかも
真(しん)ちゃんが手こずってる
We expected this from Rakuzan!
さすが洛山
ディフェンスひとつとっても—
Their defense is strong!
鍛え方ハンパねえ！
へっ…
ま だと思ってたけどねっ
But we knew it would be!
All right, a one-on-one! Come on!
よっしゃあ ワンオンワン！
来い！
はっははー
なに目とか輝かせてんだ おーい
What are you getting so excited about, huh?
（宮地）ひくぞ！
木村の軽トラで
I'll run you over with Kimura's truck!
Huh? He's good at dribbling!
（葉山）あり？
ドリブルうっまー！
（大坪･宮地）よっしゃあ！
Yeah!
Hey! How could you just let them pass you?
おい！
何シャラッと抜かれとんじゃい！
ゴメン
Sorry.
You're not asleep, are you?
（実渕）ちょっと〜
寝てんじゃないでしょうね？
しっかりしてよ
Keep it together.
Sorry, sorry.
ゴメンゴメン！
Kotaro.
わあっ！
ちゃんと返すから！
I'll get them back!
Don't be mad, Akashi!
怒んないで 赤司！
That's fine, but if you don't
want to play, I'll sub you out.
ならばいいが—
やる気がないなら交代してもらうよ
I'm fine!
ダイジョーブ！
No one's better at dribbling than me!
ドリブルなら
誰にも負けねえもんねっ！
（観客１）おお 葉山！
Hayama!
Will he get his revenge already?
（観客２）いきなり
やり返すのか!?
What? You're not going anywhere.
はあ？ させねえよ
No, I'm going to do it.
いーや やるもんね
Three should do it.
３本でいいかな？
（宮地）は… ３本？
Three?
The harder you dribble,
（高尾）ドリブルってのは—
強く突くほどボールが速く
取られにくい
the faster the ball travels and the
more difficult it is to control.
But that...
けど なんつう…
（赤司）さっきの言葉
（緑間）ん？
If you had trouble understanding
me earlier, allow me to rephrase.
（赤司）
分かりにくければ言い直そう
（宮地）何だ このドリブル
目で追えねえ
How is he dribbling like that?
My eyes can't keep up!
いや…
It disappeared?
消えた！
（赤司）僕が直接
手を下すまでもない
I don't need to do anything myself.
That's all.
それだけのことだよ
Preview
Shintaro, you are strong.
（赤司）真太郎 オマエは強い
だが結果は見えている
However, I know how this will end.
Don't underestimate Shutoku, Akashi.
（緑間）秀徳をナメるなよ 赤司
I know you better than anyone else.
オマエのことは
オレが一番よく知っている
I will defeat you.
絶対に倒す！
I Don't Know
（赤司）不撓(ふとう)不屈 その精神が
どこまでもつか試してやろう
You are determined.
Let's see how long that spirit lasts.